What's up, y'all?
Y'all great?
It's great to be here.
What does it mean to be here in support
of Lavonte on this day? It's incredible.
Um you know, what people will talk about
what he was
to everybody else,
he was something completely different to
me.
And you guys have had to feel my wrath
before.
I took it personally when it came to him
because I consider him my little brother
in every facet of the game, outside of
the building. So, when y'all see me talk
about him online, when y'all see me talk
about him on TV, right now,
anybody with a younger sibling knows
what I'm talking about. And that is
took that as a duty of mine. So, we've
had a bunch of conversations leading up
to this and uh
I'm excited for him, man. I'm excited
for him to experience life. You know, I
had to find out it's so much life out
here outside of football.
A lot of life. A lot of great life. And
I'm excited for him to be able to
experience it. Gerald, you recognized
his greatness early.
>> Mhm. Yeah. to see him rise to the
occasion and win a Super Bowl for for
your team. Oh, man.
Just just talk about the rise of Lavonte
David that you were a part of Yeah. and
witnessed. So, I remember when
when the Bucs first won a Super Bowl, a
lot of people thought that I had an
issue with the Bucs winning Super Bowl
cuz I was here for so long. And
the reason
that that was wrong is because
people have to understand,
I went through that time with these
players.
So, to see them cross over to that
threshold of being champs,
all I could think of is all of those
dark days, all of those meetings, all of
those times where we sitting in there
trying to figure it out. And and then to
see them hold that trophy up, that meant
more to me than probably anybody because
I know what they went through to get to
that point. And to see a person like
Lavonte
be able to play the way he played
leading up to it and especially in that
game, oh man, that was the greatest
feeling ever. So, when I talked to him
all the time, I remember he did an
interview the other day and I seen the
trophy in the background and it just I
smiled so big, especially he's up here
talking about it.
I love to see the people I love win
in whatever they're doing. So, when it
comes to this locker room and this
organization, man,
I meant what I said. I've been a fan of
this organization since I was a tyke.
Started with Sapp and then it ventured
out to the whole team and now the
organization. So, people forget that
when you play the game, it doesn't take
away the fandom. I was a fan first. So,
I took myself outside of the player and
put myself in fan mode. So, that's why I
called him like, "Hey, when y'all win
this thing, I need you to FaceTime me so
I can celebrate with y'all." He missed
the memo cuz he FaceTimed me after the
locker room was empty. I said, "No, I
wanted to beat." Whatever. So, yeah. But
yeah, to see what he's been and to do
that and then continue it continue it
even going out with a win, freaking
incredible. What did you play with
Lavonte? I think I played with Lavonte
David for so many seasons. Mhm. What are
some of the biggest things that he drove
you and your team against both the way
he played the game on the field and how
you would prepare during the week in
practice and film room, etc. Yeah, so
I would say uh
Dan Orlovsky,
uh Fitz, Luke Kuechly,
and Lavonte, probably the greatest and
Keith Tandy, probably the greatest
football minds I've ever been around.
Uh
and then when you partner
his ability to play the way he could,
I call him the Flash for a reason.
You partner his mind and his preparation
and how he approached the game
and you get to watch it. You know, I was
a big process guy.
Uh you guys seen the finished product.
Y'all would see the first portion of
practice, which is you know, kind of
individual, but the meetings and all
that, there's a lot that goes into it.
To see his process
and to see him put it all together and
then
watch him perform,
that's why I say uh Sapp,
Aaron Donald,
Aaron Rodgers, and Lavonte David are my
favorite football players of all time.
Lavonte because I was able to
be next to him. But then to see his
process and then see the finished
product on Sundays,
you guys got to watch the finished
product. If y'all seen what went into
him being what he was, you it would
y'all's respect is here, it would be
unmatched. If you if you had an
opportunity to pitch him to the Pro
Football Hall of Fame voters, what would
you say?
Just
you take
what he's done
and put it next to all of the greats.
Take the name off of it.
Look at what he's done
and just
Super Bowl, did that. Multiple playoffs,
did that. He's got the tackles, he's got
the takeaways.
Whatever you want, whatever metric you
want, stayed out of trouble. No issue,
nothing.
Put it next to those greats. If you just
take the numbers and the accolades and
just put the accolades up. Don't put the
name on it. And you say, "That's a Hall
of Famer. That's a Hall of Famer. That's
a Hall of Famer. That's a Hall of
Famer."
One of those names, when you start
putting names on it, will be Lavonte
David.
And that's what I would pitch to them.
And that's why
I will scream from the mountaintop
as much as I need to for Lavonte David
to be in the Hall of Fame. He is a Hall
of Fame If his career is not Hall of
Fame worthy,
I don't know.
Gerald, this time it comes on his own
terms, obviously.
>> Yeah.
The I think the retirement for players
and this is all you've ever done your
whole life, there's this great unknown,
right? And so I'm sure that there's a
lot of fear. Did he talk to you about
that as he kind of contemplated like
what's next? I mean, you having gone
through it, like not sure what's behind
that
>> Yeah, of course. That's That's That's
honestly the reason why a lot of us
football players, we struggle with
retiring or moving on is because
our lives have been so structured in one
way for so long. You've done this for so
He said he'd been playing football for
30 years. But then when you get to a
certain level, everything is done. Bing
bing bing bing bing, next year. Bing
bing. It's done this way for so long.
The unknown is a scary part.
And I my encouragement to him was
all of us football players, it does not
matter who you see in front of this
camera.
When we step on that field, we all
create personas to be able to play the
game at the level we do.
Whatever that is. Sometimes you see guys
have all of this be so animated on the
field and then you talk to them in
person, it's like, "That's not the
same." We all do it. Everybody. Any
football player that tell you they don't
is lying.
We all create these personas to go
perform the way we do.
This is what I told Lavonte.
The person that you
go home to and look in the mirror,
that's up here in your head,
that is the person that you need to be
okay going to be
because that's Lavonte.
And once you realize who that person is,
you're going to find out really quick
they're going to love that person
just as much, if not more. So, I told
him, "Go be that.
Go get married. Go have more kids. Go
experience other ventures. It's so much
life out here.
Go enjoy your life.
He's given this game everything he has.
There's no more to give to the game. So,
go experience life."
Okay. Thanks, Gerald. All right, thanks,
everybody. Do you know how many people